<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://johnthenerd.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on John&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://johnthenerd.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making my local LLM voice assistant faster and more scalable with RAG</title>
      <link>https://johnthenerd.com/blog/faster-local-llm-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnthenerd.com/blog/faster-local-llm-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you read &lt;a href=&#34;../local-llm-assistant&#34;&gt;my previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, you probably already know that I like my smart home open-source and very local, and that certainly includes any voice assistant I may have. If you watched the video demo, you have probably also found out that it&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; slow. Trust me, I did too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prefix caching helps, but it feels like cheating. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;ll look amazing in a demo, but as soon as I start using my LLM for other things (which I do, quite often), that cache is going to get evicted and that first prompt is still going to be slow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a fully local LLM voice assistant to control my smart home</title>
      <link>https://johnthenerd.com/blog/local-llm-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnthenerd.com/blog/local-llm-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had my days with Siri and Google Assistant. While they have the ability to control your devices, they cannot be customized and inherently rely on cloud services. In hopes of learning something new &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; having something cool I could use in my life, I decided I want better.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The premises are simple:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I want my new assistant to be sassy and sarcastic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I want everything running local. No exceptions. There is no reason for my coffee machine downstairs to talk to a server on the other side of the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-hosting and NAT Loopback</title>
      <link>https://johnthenerd.com/blog/nat-loopback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnthenerd.com/blog/nat-loopback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started hosting my services, I quickly ran into a major problem. Everything was timing out, but it was somehow working just fine when I was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; connected to my home network! So turns out, this was because my router does not support what&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_address_translation#NAT_hairpinning&#34;&gt;NAT Loopback&lt;/a&gt; (also called NAT Hairpinning).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like many things you&amp;rsquo;ll see in production, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=17GtmwyvmWE&amp;amp;feature=share&amp;amp;t=26m18s&#34;&gt;the 32-bit address space of IPv4 was meant to be for a prototype&lt;/a&gt;. This limits the total number of IP addresses to 2^32, which is 4,294,967,296. Unfortunately, nowadays that&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near enough. The real solution is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPv6&#34;&gt;IPv6&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/intl/en/ipv6/statistics.html#tab=per-country-ipv6-adoption&#34;&gt;adoption is extremely poor&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_address_translation&#34;&gt;NAT&lt;/a&gt; is the necessary evil that keeps things running. It works by sharing a single IPv4 address across an entire household, where the individual devices are assigned &amp;ldquo;private IP addresses&amp;rdquo; from the list defined in &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc1918&#34;&gt;RFC1918&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://johnthenerd.com/403/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnthenerd.com/403/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;forbidden&#34;&gt;Forbidden!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You were denied access to this server. This could be for any one of the below reasons:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You mistyped the address or tried to access this server from a very old browser that lacks support for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudflare.com/en-ca/learning/ssl/what-is-sni/&#34;&gt;TLS SNI&lt;/a&gt;. Any browser that is even remotely recent should work fine, but if you are using Internet Explorer 6, you just might want to upgrade.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You were trying to log in somewhere and your credentials were not valid.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Your IP address is considered spam by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crowdsec.net/&#34;&gt;CrowdSec&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dnsbl.info/&#34;&gt;DNSBL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SpiderLabs/ModSecurity&#34;&gt;ModSecurity&lt;/a&gt; did not like what you are trying to do. This typically only happens if you are trying to exploit common vulnerabilities on my website.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You have been banned by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bunkerity/bunkerweb&#34;&gt;BunkerWeb&lt;/a&gt;. It will automatically ban IP addresses by observing bad behavior.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If none of the above are true, feel free to contact me so I can try to fix the issue for you! Please include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://johnthenerd.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnthenerd.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;turtletale&#34;&gt;TurtleTale&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A browser-based 2D platformer about a young turtle, complete with a level editor, an in-game shop to purchase permanent upgrades, and toggleable cheats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://johnthenerd.com/turtletale&#34;&gt;https://johnthenerd.com/turtletale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;wolrelay&#34;&gt;WOLRelay&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Python Wake-on-LAN forwarder that is able to listen for ARP reply packets to track IP addresses without any agent process running on the target machine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JohnTheNerd/WOLRelay&#34;&gt;https://github.com/JohnTheNerd/WOLRelay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;pysarra&#34;&gt;PySarra&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Python client for Environment Canada&amp;rsquo;s Sarracenia service that is designed to be easy to use. It uses AMQP to talk to Environment Canada&amp;rsquo;s public servers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
